Marietta Simpson Collection, 1967-2019 SC 168
Archives of African American Music and Culture
- 5. Programs
  - 5.1. Simpson Concerts and Recitals, 1975-2019, undated
    - Vocal Extravaganza, National Association of Negro Musicians 2011 Convention (Bright Hope Baptist Church, Philadelphia, PA), 2011-07-25 (Box: 15, Folder 12)
    - Handel: Messiah, US Naval Academy Distinguished Artists Series (Annapolis, MD), 2011-12 (Box: 15, Folder 13)
    - Farewell to Karen Hanson, Indiana University, 2012-01-12 (Box: 15, Folder 14)
    - Honoring Dr. Martin Luther King J., Indiana University, 2012-01-15 (Box: 15, Folder 14)
    - Dave's Diamond Jubilee Birthday Lunch, 2012-04-14 (Box: 15, Folder 14)
    - Jillian Richards Wedding, First United Methodist Church, 2012-06-16 (Box: 15, Folder 14)
    - Bruckner: Te Deum; Tippett: A Child of Our Time, Collegiate Chorale (Carnegie Hall), 2012-02-03 (Box: 15, Folder 15)
    - An Evening With Black Artists, Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity (West Palm Beach, FL), 2012-02-11 (Box: 15, Folder 16)
    - 50th Founder Celebration, Pastor Rosie Wallace, First Church of Love Faith & Deliverance (Voorhees, NJ), 2012-06-22 (Box: 15, Folder 17)
    - Sunday Service, Unitarian Society of Germantown, 2012-09-02 (Box: 15, Folder 18)
    - A Celebration of Spirituals, African American Choral Ensemble and Singing Hoosiers, Indiana University, 2013-01-27 (Box: 15, Folder 19)
    - 25th Wedding Anniversary Celebration (Voorhees, NJ), 2013-06-29 (Box: 15, Folder 19)
    - Dedication of the East Studio Building, Indiana University, 2013-10-31 (Box: 15, Folder 19)
    - Hammerstein/Kern: Show Boat (Queenie), Houston Grand Opera, 2013-01-2013-02 (Box: 15, Folder 20)
    - Inspired by the Spiritual, Astral Artists (Church of the Holy Trinity, Philadelphia, PA), 2013-02-16 (Box: 15, Folder 21)
    - Mozart: Requiem, Baltimore Symphony Orchestra, 2013-02-28 (Box: 15, Folder 22)
    - Mozart: Requiem, Baltimore Symphony Orchestra, 2013-03 (Box: 15, Folder 23)
    - Mendelssohn: Elijah, Bach Choir of Bethlehem (First Presbyterian Church of Bethlehem, PA), 2013-03-10 (Box: 15, Folder 24)
    - Bach: Mass in B Minor, Baltimore Choral Arts Society, 2013-10-27 (Box: 15, Folder 25)
    - Handel: Messiah, Shiloh Baptist Church, 2013-12-08 (Box: 15, Folder 26)
    - Recital with Julietta Curenton, Philadelphia Chamber Music Society, 2014-03-09 (Box: 15, Folder 27)
    - Handel: Messiah, Hartford Memorial Baptist Church (Detroit, MI), 2014-12-21 (Box: 15, Folder 28)
    - AIT Winter Recital, Opera Theatre of St. Louis (Graham Chapel, Washington University), 2015-01-18 (Box: 15, Folder 29)
    - Dedication of Anniversary Plaza and Cindy's Song, Indiana University, 2015-04-10 (Box: 15, Folder 29)
    - Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. Day Celebration Leadership Breakfast, Indiana University, 2005-01-19 (Box: 15, Folder 29)
    - Steve Zegree: A Celebration of Life, Indiana University, 2015-04-19 (Box: 15, Folder 29)
    - Bach: St. Matthew Passion, Mendelssohn Club of Philadelphia, 2015-02-18 (Box: 15, Folder 30)
    - Bernstein: Candide (The Old Lady), Glimmerglass Festival 40, 2015-07-2015-08 (Box: 16, Folder 1)
    - Masterclass, Indiana Music Teachers Association 2015 Conference, Vincennes University, 2015-09 (Box: 16, Folder 2)
    - Handel: Messiah, Hartford Memorial Baptist Church, 2015-12 (Box: 16, Folder 3)
    - Masterclass, NATS, Mason George University, 2016-02 (Box: 16, Folder 4)
    - J. Szymko: Shadow & Light, Eugene Vocal Arts and Concert Orchestra (University of Oregon), 2016-04 (Box: 16, Folder 5)
    - A Historical Odyssey, From the Cradle to Liberation, In Celebration of the Grand Opening of the Smithsonian National Museum of African American History & Culture (Shiloh Baptist Church, Washington, DC), 2016-09-18 (Box: 16, Folder 6)
    - Bernstein: Candide, Theatre Du Capitole, 2016-12 (Box: 16, Folder 7)
    - Service of Witness to the Resurrection, In Loving Memory of Manuel "Manny" Barreiro, 2017-12 (Box: 16, Folder 8)
    - College Audition Preparation CAP Faculty Recital, Indiana University, 2017-07-29 (Box: 16, Folder 8)
    - Sylvia & Friends, A Program of More Love Songs Benefitting Shalom Community Center (Bloomington, IN), 2017-10-15 (Box: 16, Folder 8)
    - Music! Music! Music!, Antiquarian and Historical Society of Culver, 2017-07-29 (Box: 16, Folder 8)
    - Steve Houghton Quintet (Jazz Fables, Bears Place, Bloomington, IN), 2017-11-02 (Box: 16, Folder 8)
    - Handel: Messiah, Hartford Memorial Baptist Church (Detroit, MI), 2017-12-17 (Box: 16, Folder 9)
    - Who is the Other? Conflict and Community in West Side Story, Indiana University, 2018-04-10 (Box: 16, Folder 10)
    - Voices of Hope in a Time of Fear, Extending the Legacy of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., First Christian Church (Bloomington, IN), 2018-01-07 (Box: 16, Folder 10)
    - Black History Month, A Celebration, Indiana University, 2018-02-18 (Box: 16, Folder 10)
    - Rutter: Feel the Spirit, Vocal Essence (St. Paul, MN), 2018-04-21 (Box: 16, Folder 11)
    - Beecher/Moscovitch: Sky on Swings (Martha), Opera Philadelphia, 2018-09 (Box: 16, Folder 12)
    - Handel: Messiah, Shiloh Baptist Church, 2018-12-09 (Box: 16, Folder 13)
    - A Soulful Christmas honoring Dottie Peoples (Kimmel Center, Philadelphia), 2018-12-11 (Box: 16, Folder 14)
    - Ho+C380:C381noring Martin Luther King Jr., Indiana University, 2019-01-20 (Box: 16, Folder 15)
    - Crooked Stick: Songs in a Strange Land (IU Archives of African American Music Presents), 2019-02-17 (Box: 16, Folder 15)
    - Florence Price Symposium, Second Presbyterian Church (Indianapolis, IN), 2019-03-08-2019-03-10 (Box: 16, Folder 16)
    - Simpson programs, undated, 2019 (Box: 16, Folder 17)
  - 5.2. Programs, IU Students and Colleagues
    - Students of Marietta Simpson, recitals, 1997-2015 (Box: 16, Folder 18)
    - IU affiliated concerts and events, 2009-2018 (Box: 16, Folder 19)
  - 5.3. Programs (Other)
    - Ernst Wolff, Carnegie Hall Recital, 1970-01-06 (Box: 16, Folder 20)
    - Maria Callas and Giuseppe di Stefano, Academy of Music Recital Program, 1974-02-11 (Box: 16, Folder 21)
    - Reconvening the First Continental Congress: Dinner program, 1974-09-06 (Box: 16, Folder 22)
    - Donald Grimm Recital Program, "Sing Out, America", 1976-04-21 (Box: 16, Folder 23)
    - Program, Joy Simpson recital, Alice Tully Hall, 1976-10-28 (Box: 16, Folder 24)
    - Singing City Tribute to Duke Ellington, Evelyn Simpson-Curenton (conductor), 1995-05-01 (Box: 16, Folder 25)
    - Wedding programs and announcements, 1993-2014 (Box: 16, Folder 26)
    - Let All The World in Every Corner Sing My God and King!, Collegiumskapelle, Kloster Mehrerau, 1997-08-17 (Box: 16, Folder 27)
    - John Aler, Faith Esham, and Warren Jones Recital (Carnegie Hall), 1998-03-13 (Box: 16, Folder 27)
    - Original Thought, Religious Conviction, Academy of the New Church Arts Council (Bryn Athyn, PA), 2001-09-2001-10 (Box: 16, Folder 27)
    - Bellingham Festival of Music (Bellingham, WA), 2004-08 (Box: 16, Folder 27)
    - Eric Owens and Lawrence Brownlee in Concert (Alice Busch Opera Theater), 2015-08-02 (Box: 16, Folder 27)
    - Robert Shaw tribute and discography, 1999-2006 (Box: 16, Folder 28)
    - Funeral Programs, Simpson Family and Friends, 2000-2009 (Box: 16, Folder 29)
    - Funeral Programs, Simpson Family and Friends, 2010-2019 (Box: 16, Folder 30)
    - Funeral programs, Bloomington, IN colleagues, 2010-2019 (Box: 16, Folder 31)
    - TrueLight Fellowship Church 20th Anniversary Program, Dr. Wesley Pinnock (founder), 2015-04-26 (Box: 16, Folder 32)
    - Patricia Marie Bradford's 60th Birthday Celebration program, 2015-11-15 (Box: 16, Folder 33)
- 6. Photographs and Albums
  - Subseries 6.1: Publicity Photographs
  - Subseries 6.2: Performance and Event Photographs
  - Subseries 6.3: Candid and Unidentified Photographs
  - Subseries 6.4: Simpson Family Photographs
  - Subseries 6.5: Photograph Albums
- 9. Audio Recordings
  - 9.1. Audiocassettes, non-commercial
    - Joy Simpson, Glencairn Concerts, tape 2, 1 Audiocassette
      Container Note
      Program contents on container insert; Sylvia Olden Lee, piano
      Shelf Number
      cass 3985
    - Joy Simpson, Glencairn Concert, tapes 3, 1986; 1 Audiocassette
      Program contents on container insert; David Lofton, piano
      cass 3986
    - Joy Simpson, "Joy Sings", 1 Audiocassette
      cass 3987
    - Joy Simpson, I've Decided to Make Jesus My Choice, 1978; 1 Audiocassette
      Evelyn Simpson Curenton, pianist; Larry Mayfield, conductor. Contents: There's Something About The Lord -- Carribean Melodies -- I've Decided To Make Jesus My Choice -- Balm In Gilead -- The Lord Is My Light (Text Psalm 27) -- Hard Trials -- I Feel Like Traveling On -- What He's Done For Me -- Jesus Is All The World To Me.
      cass 3988
    - Joy Simpson, Capital University, Columbus, Ohio, 1981-07-27; 1 Audiocassette
      Mascagni's Cavalleria rusticana, role of Santuzza
      cass 3989
    - Marietta Simpson, Menotti's Amahl and the Night Visitors, 1970; 1 Audiocassette
      Performing the role of Mother at age 14.
      cass 3990
    - Marietta Simpson, Bach's Passion According to St. Matthew, 2000-04-20; 2 Audiocassette
      The Cleveland Orchestra; Christoph von Dohnanyi, conductor.
      cass 3991-3992
    - Marietta Simpson, Tchaikovsky and Russian song coaching, 1994-01; 1 Audiocassette
      Voice coach: Oksana Bryn.
      cass 3993
    - Marietta Simpson, Weill Recital Hall, 1995-02-24; 1 Audiocassette
      Carnegie Hall Presents Marietta Simpson, mezzo-soprano, Evelyn Simpson-Curenton, piano. Note on label: 1st half tape #1
      cass 3994
    - Marietta Simpson, Settlement Music School Sunday Brunch Benefit, 1995-05-07; 1 Audiocassette
      Recorded live at the Hotel Atop the Bellevue, Grand Ballroom for broadcast on WFLN-FM
      cass 3995
    - Handel, Giulio Cesare in Egitto, St. Paul Chamber Orchestra, 1994-03-27; 1 Audiocassette
      cass 3996
    - Marietta Simpson Recital, Matinee Musicale, Cincinnati, OH, 1993-10-12; 1 Audiocassette
      cass 3997
    - Marietta Simpson, 1994-03-24-1994-03-26; 1 Audiocassette
      cass 3998
    - Marietta Simpson, Weill Recital Hall, second half, 1995-02-24; 1 Audiocassette
      cass 3999
    - Bach, Saint John Passion, 1994-04-01; 2 Audiocassette
      Ordway Music Theater, Saint Paul, MN
      cass 4000-4001
    - Mahler, Symphony No. 2, Rehearsal, 1992; 1 Audiocassette
      Knoxville, TN
      cass 4002
    - Handel, Giulio Cesare in Egitto, Rehearsal, 1994-01-19; 1 Audiocassette
      Marietta Simpson, Cornelia
      cass 4003
    - Ambassadors Chorale and Ensemble with George Shirley, 1991-11-29; 1 Audiocassette
      Mt. Zion Baptist Church of Germantown, PA
      cass 4004
    - Mozart, Vesperae solennes de confessore, K339, 1993-03-27; 1 Audiocassette
      cass 4005
    - The Mikado coaching with Stephen Lord, 1 Audiocassette
      cass 4006
    - Lesson with Carmen, 1 Audiocassette
      cass 4007
    - Marietta and Evelyn Concert, 1987-05-30; 1 Audiocassette
      cass 4008
    - Marietta and Evelyn Concert, 1987-05-30; 1 Audiocassette
      High Street Church of God [Philadelphia, PA]
      cass 4009
    - NY Recital Music, 1 Audiocassette
      Container spine: Love Songs.
      cass 4010
    - Marietta Simpson: The Hits, 1 Audiocassette
      cass 4011
    - Pastor Glen Spaulding: The Secret Place, 2006-12-31; 1 Audiocassette
      cass 4012
    - Marietta Simpson performance with orchestra (unidentified), 1 Audiocassette
      cass 4013
    - Marietta Simpson, Interview or performance? (low levels), 1 Audiocassette
      cass 4014
    - Marietta Simpson private lesson with voice student? (side A), 1 Audiocassette
      cass 4015
    - Marietta Simpson recital, Columbia University Miller Theatre?, 1994-02-17; 1 Audiocassette
      Accompanied by Evelyn Simpson-Curenton?
      cass 4016
    - Marietta Simpson receiving a private voice lesson (side A), 1 Audiocassette
      cass 4017
    - Marietta Simpson, Copland: Old American Songs, 2000-01-06; 1 Audiocassette
      Colorado Symphony Orchestra
      cass 4018
    - Seven Last Words, 1 Audiocassette
      Performers listed on insert: John Austin, Evelyn, organ; Ava Williams?, Gregory Hopkins, Becky, Daddy, Evelyn
      cass 4019
    - Joy Simpson "More Than Music" Memorial on KNBI, 1987-03-29; 1 Audiocassette
      cass 4020
    - Joy Simpson Recital in Johannesburg, 1987-03; 1 Audiocassette
      Accompanying letter from Jonathan Sternberg on October 26, 1987 (box 5/folder 5): The enclosed cassette has a performance which Joy and I did in Johannesburg just a few days before the tragedy. If is a beautiful rendition of the Barber "Knoxville: Summer of 1915" as well as 2 spirituals.
      cass 4021
    - Robert Shaw Tribute; Excerpts from Performance Today, 1999-01-26; 1 Audiocassette
      Housed in oversive container
      cass 4022
    - Robert Shaw: A Celebration (Symphony Hall, Atlanta, GA), 1999-01-26; 1 Audiocassette
      cass 4023
  - 9.2. Compact Discs, non-commercial
  - 9.3. Compact Discs, Commercial
    - Vivaldi - Gloria; Bach - Magnificat // Robert Shaw; Atlanta Symphony Orchestra & Chamber Chorus, 1989; 1 Audio Disc CD
      Online Access
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/b88q382h0d
      CD 11872
    - Schubert - Mass No. 2 & Mass No. 6 // Robert Shaw & Atlanta Symphony Orchestra & Choruses, 1990; 1 Audio Disc CD
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/j33307101g
      CD 11873
    - Stabat Mater (Szymanowski); Stabat Mater (Poulenc) // Robert Shaw & Atlanta Symphony Orchestra & Chorus, 1994; 1 Audio Disc CD
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/9601984c8j
      CD 11874
    - Songs Of Reflection: 8 Vocal and 7 Choral Arrangements of Moses Hogan, 1997; 1 Audio Disc CD
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/z60c87wf26
      CD 11875
    - Christmas in Bethlehem Vol. 3 // The Bach Choir of Bethlehem, 2002; 1 Audio Disc CD
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/m90d86vt9z
      CD 11876
    - Dvořák - Stabat Mater // Robert Shaw & Atlanta Symphony Orchestra and Chorus, 1999; 2 Audio Discs CD
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/b09j13gq1r
      CD 11877
    - Janáček - Glagolitic Mass; Dvořák - Te Deum // Robert Shaw & Atlanta Symphony Orchestra & Chorus, 1991; 1 Audio Disc CD
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/g25742h239
      CD 11878
    - Beethoven - Mass in C major; Elegiac Song; Calm Sea and Prosperous Voyage // Robert Shaw & Atlanta Symphony Orchestra & Chorus, 1990; 1 Audio Disc CD
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/x51h543n8k
      CD 11879
    - J. S. Bach - Mass in B Minor // The Bach Choir of Bethlehem with The Bach Festival Orchestra, 1998; 2 Audio Discs CD
      https://media.dlib.indiana.edu/media_objects/nz806j674
      CD 11880
    - William Bolcom - Songs of Innocence and of Experience (William Blake) // University of Michigan School of Music Symphony Orchestra; University Musical Society; Leonard Slatkin, 2004; 3 Audio Discs CD
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/g84m60xd13
      CD 11881
    - J. S. Bach - Christmas Oratorio // The Bach Choir of Bethlehem with The Bach Festival Orchestra, 1999; 2 Audio Discs CD
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/772039rt07
      CD 11882